<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="dig-eg-gaz.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">1906-7 Vade Mecum template</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2019-11-19">November 19, 2019</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1908-01-28">January 28, 1908</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="7" xml:id="deg-el-vmhb02">
                <div type="masthead">
                    <cols n="3"/>
                    <cb n="1"/>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>PICTURE POST CARDS.</head>
                        <p>"The Egyptian Gazette" Series is the most artistic collection to be found
                            in Egypt.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cb n="2"/>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Vade Mecum for the Homeward Bound</head>
                    </div>
                    <cb n="6"/>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>Picture Post Cards</head>
                        <p>"The Egyptian Gazette" Series is the most artistic collection to be found
                            in Egypt.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cols n="6"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>TO OUR VISITORS</head>
                    <p>The Egyptian Gazette has much pleasure in presenting to its subscribers the
                        accompanying description of some of the many interesting routes by which
                        they may travel homewards. Great care has been taken to arrange them as
                        accurately and concisely as possible, and it will be found that none of them
                        are fraught with difficulty. In choosing the route home there are several
                        things to be considered. To begin with there is the difference in climate
                        between Egypt and the various points at which you may arrive in Europe.</p>
                    <cb n="2"/>
                    <p>This depends partly upon the month in which you leave Egypt, for Cairo in
                        January may be a little warmer than the Riviera and possibly not so warm as
                        Sicily, but in March it will be warmer than Rome, and more uniformly warm
                        than many other places in Europe. Many people leave Egypt far too early in
                        the year, for as a rule the weather in April and May is perfect. The warmest
                        place to go to on leaving Egypt is Sicily.</p>
                    <p>Some will want to take into consideration the number of days to be spent at
                        sea, and we therefore subjoin a list shewing the time occupied on each of
                        the various routes between Egypt and the Continent of Europe.</p>
                    <p><cb n="3"/></p>
                    <p>They are as follows:—</p>
                    <p>The long sea routes—from Port Said or Alexandria to Plymouth, Southhampton,
                        London or Liverpool—occupy about 14 days. The short ones are as
                        follows:—</p>
                    <table cols="4">
                        <row>
                            <cell>Port Said or Alexandria</cell>
                            <cell>to Brindisi</cell>
                            <cell>3 days</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Alexandria </cell>
                            <cell>to Messina</cell>
                            <cell>3 ,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Port Said or Alexandria</cell>
                            <cell>to Marseilles</cell>
                            <cell>5 ,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Alexandria</cell>
                            <cell>to Venice and Trieste</cell>
                            <cell>3½ ,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Alexandria</cell>
                            <cell>to Naples</cell>
                            <cell>3 ,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Port Said</cell>
                            <cell>to Genoa</cell>
                            <cell>5 ,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Port Said</cell>
                            <cell>to Naples</cell>
                            <cell>4 ,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Alexandria</cell>
                            <cell>to Constantinople</cell>
                            <cell>4 ,, </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Alexandria</cell>
                            <cell>to Piraeus</cell>
                            <cell>2 ,,</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <cell>Port Said</cell>
                            <cell>to Gibraltar</cell>
                            <cell>7 ,,</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <cb n="4"/>
                    <p>The steamers of the P.&amp; O., the Egyptian Mail S.S,. Co., North German
                        Lloyd, Orient, and Messageries Maritimes are the largest. The Anchor,
                        British India, Bibby and Henderson Lines are also excellent, and their
                        steamers are largely patronised by travellers to Egypt.</p>
                    <p>As regards the train journeys from Cairo, the shortest is that to Alexandria,
                        without change (3 hours). That to Port Said can now be made without change
                        in 4 ½ hours.</p>
                    <p>The least expensive way to England is by the Moss, Papayanni, Prince, and
                        Westcott lines of steamers from Alexandria to Liverpool. The German Levant
                        line has also good steamers from Alexandria to Hamburg.</p>
                    <cb n="5"/>
                    <p>The quickest through Continental routes are by P.&amp; O. Brindisi express
                        from Port Said, by the Egyptian Mail S.S. Co., from Alexandria to Marseilles
                        and the Austrian Lloyd Trieste Vienna express from Alexandria.</p>
                    <p>As regards heavy luggage, it must be borne in mind that very little luggage
                        is allowed free on the railways of Europe, but there are several good and
                        responsible forwarding agents in Egypt who undertake at a fixed charge to
                        deliver packages to any address in Europe. The Egyptian Mail S.S. Co., have
                        also made arrangements whereby luggage can be collected and sent to any
                        address.</p>
                    <p>The quickest manner of getting to Europe from Port Said is undoubtedly by the
                        fast Mail Steamers “Osiris" and “Isis” to Brindisi. One of these leaves Port
                        Said every week, as soon as possible after receiving the Indian <cb n="6"
                        />mails from the great liner arrived from Bombay.</p>
                    <p>These small but comfortable ships have enormously powerful engines, and
                        attain a very high rate of speed. They are called the "Ferry Boats" having
                        been specially built to carry the British mail from Port Said to Brindisi.
                        If you are going straight through to England you will find the train waiting
                        at Brindisi which will take you to Calais without changing. It has complete
                        arrangements for sleeping and eating on board, and you should arrive in
                        London on the fifth day from leaving Port Said.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>HOTELS EN ROUTE.</head>
                    <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                        <head>SYRACUSE </head>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL</p>
                        <p>PIAZZA MAZZINI, SYRACUSE (Sicily)</p>
                        <p>First Hotel in the Town.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>SYRACUSE (Sicily.)</head>
                        <p>HOTEL DES ETRANGERS. </p>
                        <p>"CASA POLITI."</p>
                        <p>First Class, Electric Light, Lift. Central Heating. </p>
                        <p>Private Baths. All Comforts. </p>
                        <p>Proprietor: Engelke-Zunke</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>TAORMINA</head>
                        <p>HOTEL METROPOLE.</p>
                        <p>First-Class House. Beautiful Position. German Management. </p>
                        <p>Same Proprietor Hotel Grande Bretagne, Catania</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>PALERMO </head>
                        <p>Villa Igiea Grand Hotel.</p>
                        <p>V. CALANTI Manager.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>SORRENTO </head>
                        <p>Hotel Tramontano</p>
                        <p>Hotels Tramontano &amp; Tasso, &amp; Hotel Pension Syrene.</p>
                        <p>These excellent Hotels, which are situated in the best part of what is
                            worthily named the "Beauty Spot of Italy," are the annual resort of the
                            most distinguished English and American families. The principal centre
                            for excursions. Electric light throughout. Tennis. English church.</p>
                        <p>Mr. G. Tamontano, Proprietor &amp; Manager.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>NAPLES </head>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL.</p>
                        <p>Unrivalled position. First Class.</p>
                        <p>Private bathrooms, Steam Heating throughout, Newest Sanitary
                            arrangements.</p>
                        <p>Hauser &amp; Doepfner. Proprs.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>The Hotel Baglioni.</head>
                        <p>First Class</p>
                        <p>EVERY MODERN COMFORT.</p>
                        <p>BRANCH HOUSE: HOTEL D'ITALIE, BOLOGNA.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>Hotel PAOLI,</head>
                        <p>FLORENCE, FULL SOUTH.</p>
                        <p>LUNGARNO DELLA ZECGA.</p>
                        <p>Beautiful view of the surrounding hills. </p>
                        <p>First class Hotel with Every Modern Comfort.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>HOTEL FLORENCE WASHINGTON.</head>
                        <p>LUNGARNO.</p>
                        <p>First Class Family House. All Modern Comforts.</p>
                        <p>Entirely Renovated.</p>
                        <p>C. GOBBO, Proprietor</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>Pisa </head>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL and HOTEL DE LONDRES,</p>
                        <p>The <hi rend="ul">only</hi> Hotel with Central Heating.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>RAPALLO</head>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL VERDI.</p>
                        <p>First Class. All Modern Comforts.</p>
                        <p>LAWN TENNIS.</p>
                        <p>P.G. SAMPIETRO</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>PENSION SHELLEY.</head>
                        <p>VIAREGGIO</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>GENOA</head>
                        <p>BRISTOL HOTEL. L. BERTOLINI</p>
                        <p>HOTEL CONTINENTAL. MERLANO ILLI.</p>
                        <p>EDEN PALACE HOTEL. CARLO BORGARELLO.</p>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL DE GENES. ROWDG. BONERA.</p>
                        <p>HOTEL HELVETIA. SWISS Prop.</p>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL ISOTTA. KIENAST SCHUCANT &amp; Co.</p>
                        <p>HOTEL DE LONDRES. FREDERICO FIORONI.</p>
                        <p>MODERN HOTEL. D. COCHIS.</p>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL SAVOIE. F. FIORONI.</p>
                        <p>HOTEL SMITH. SMITH BROS.</p>
                        <p>HOTEL RESTAURANT RIGHI. E. CHRISTEN.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>SALSOMAGGIORE </head>
                        <p>HOTEL CENTRAL BAGNI.</p>
                        <p>The most recently built Hotel in Salsomaggiore, and on which no expense
                            has been spared to render it completely up-to-date as regards hygiene
                            and comfort. The Hotel is directly connected with the New Bathing
                            Establishment by a covered passage.</p>
                        <p>Charges Moderate. Steam Heating.</p>
                        <p>For prospectus and particulars apply to the Manager.</p>
                        <p>Telegraphic Address: Central Salsomaggiore.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <cb n="2"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SICILY.</head>
                    <p>The direct route to Sicily is by the Florio-Rubattino Co.’s steamers which
                        leave Alexandria weekly for MESSINA, where one takes train to TAORMENA, one
                        of the most charming and popular places on the island. <hi rend="italic"
                            >Giardini</hi> is the station at which to alight, and the drive up to
                        Taormina is most delightful, occupying about one hour. In and around the
                        town is much to interest the visitor. The theatre is of Greek origin, but
                        restored under the Romans. CATANIA is the starting place for the ascent of
                        Etna, and here also is a fine Cathedral. The Greek, Roman, and Saracenic
                        remains that are found all over the island, are an endless sources of
                        pleasure. SYRACUSE has an interesting history, having been a Greek city,
                        which was designed by Demosthenes in B.C. 413, and taken by the Romans in
                        B.C. 212, when Archimedes was slain—his tomb is to be seen. The cathedral
                        was once an ancient pagan temple. PALERMO, with about 300,000 inhabitants,
                        is the capital of the Island, and enjoys a delightful climate. Much of
                        interest is to be found in this fine city. <hi rend="italic">The Palazzo
                            Reale</hi> is of Saracenic origin and close to it the church of <hi
                            rend="italic">S. Giovannia degli Eremiti</hi> with its picturesque
                        cloisters. The Cathedral, Museum, Botanic Gardens, Villa Giulia and Royal
                        Park are also worth a visit.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CENTRAL ITALY.</head>
                    <p>The fine steamers of the North German Lloyd leave Alexandria every Wednesday
                        during the season for Naples, the voyage being only 3 days.</p>
                    <p>NAPLES is also reached in 10 hours from Palermo by the Florio-Rubattino Co.’s
                        steamers, which leave daily. One cannot approach Naples or leave it without
                        wishing to explore some of its islands, besides the lovely places on its
                            bay—<hi rend="italic">Castellamare</hi> and <hi rend="italic"
                            >Sorrento</hi>. The small steamer that takes you to Sorrento [you can
                        drive too] will take you on to Capri.</p>
                    <p>From Naples to ROME is a train journey of but five hours. All who can will
                        devote at least one week to visiting the many historical and interesting
                        portions of the Eternal City, whose charms and beauties are too well-known
                        to need comment here.</p>
                    <p>Leaving the Eternal City with much regret, a railway journey of five hours
                        brings you to FLORENCE, where another week can well be spent admiring the
                            <hi rend="italic">City of Flowers</hi> and its surrounding country. In
                        Florence itself the churches and galleries are of absorbing interest, whilst
                        the local promenades and excursions should not be omitted. <hi rend="italic"
                            >The Cascine</hi> is the most attractive and fashionable promenade in
                        Florence, whilst the <hi rend="italic">Viale dei Colli</hi>, one of the
                        finest walks in Europe, opened 35 years ago, goes winding up through the
                        hills a distance of four miles. The most delightful excursion outside
                        Florence is that to <hi rend="italic">Vallombrosa</hi>, with its <hi
                            rend="italic">Monastery</hi> 3,300 feet above the sea level. This is
                        made first by ordinary train from Florence to <hi rend="italic">St.
                            Ellero</hi>, thence by cog-wheel railway to <hi rend="italic"
                            >Saltino</hi>. The ascent through groves of oaks takes an hour, and most
                        striking panoramas are unfolded to view.</p>
                    <p>PISA is easily reached from Florence in about 2 hours ; here there is a fine
                        Cathedral and the Leaning Tower. A stay of at least one night should if
                        possible be made in order to enjoy the view from the Campanile at
                        sunset.</p>
                    <p>VIAREGGIO. One of the most delightful places on the Italian Riviera near Pisa
                        and on the main line from Rome to Genoa. It is a very convenient half-way
                        house between Egypt and England, and where living is reasonable and the air
                        and surroundings exceptionally good.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NORTHERN ITALY</head>
                    <p>GENOA (La Superba).—The most picturesque and interesting city in Italy, with
                        the record of having one of the lowest death averages of European cities and
                        a phenomenally equable temperature—warm in winter and deliciously cool
                        breezes from the surrounding mountains and the Mediterranean in summer.</p>
                    <p>The patriarchal home of Italy’s most ancient nobility, whose palaces,
                        gardens, and famous collections of statuary, frescoes, and paintings, are a
                        constant delight to thousands of travellers who annually sojourn in Genoa.
                        Then there are the superbly decorated medieval churches containing exquisite
                        marble columns and historical paintings, and the incomparable Campo Santo
                        filled with its wonderful tombs.</p>
                    <p>From Genoa to Milan is a matter of only three hours by rail.</p>
                    <p>MILAN is a good centre for Northern Italy before making the tour of the
                        Lakes. The Cathedral is the principal attraction, with its beautiful windows
                        illustrating the History of the Bible. The public gardens and the monumental
                        cemetery are also worth a visit.</p>
                    <p>Between Bologna and Milan and only an hour and a half from Milan is
                        SALSOMAGGIORE, a renowned health resort on account of its thermal springs,
                        change trains at <hi rend="italic">Borgo San Domino</hi> and in half-an-hour
                        you are at Salsomaggiore.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>HOTELS EN ROUTE.</head>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>SYRACUSE</head>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL VILLA POLITI. </p>
                        <p>NEWLY ENLARGED and thorougly refurnished. Electric Light throughout.
                            Central Heating in every room. Beautiful Gardens. </p>
                        <p>Concerts daily. New Proprietor,</p>
                        <p>GUSTAV KOCKEL also of the </p>
                        <p>Hotel Crande Bretagne <hi rend="italic">Catania</hi> and </p>
                        <p>Hotel Metropole <hi rend="italic">Taormina</hi>
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>TAORMINA.</head>
                        <p>SAN DOMENICO PALACE HOTEL.</p>
                        <p>FIRST CLASS. EVERY COMFORT.</p>
                        <p>A. OMARINI, Manager.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>PALERMO</head>
                        <p>HOTEL DE FRANCE.</p>
                        <p>First Class, with Pavillon on the sea Electric Light. Lift. Winter
                            Garden. 100 Rooms, nearly all sunny Best and Healthiest Situation.</p>
                        <p>P. WEINEN, Proprietor and Manager.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cols n="3"/>
                    <cb n="2"/>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>PALERMO (Sicily).</head>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL TRINACRIA</p>
                        <p>The ONLY Hotel in Palermo facing the Sea Central Heating Electric Lift
                            and Light </p>
                        <p>Private and Public Bathroowns. </p>
                        <p>ROMAN HEYN Manager. </p>
                        <p>Formerly at the Hotel Cecil London. </p>
                    </div>
                    <cols n="6"/>
                    <cb n="3"/>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>NAPLES.</head>
                        <p>SANTA LUCIA HOTEL.</p>
                        <p>FIRST CLASS</p>
                        <p>Every Modern Comfort.</p>
                        <p>Central Heating. Private Baths. Etc.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cols n="3"/>
                    <cb n="2"/>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>NAPLES </head>
                        <p>GD HOTEL DU VESUVE.</p>
                        <p>FIRST CLASS LATEST COMFORTS.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cols n="6"/>
                    <cb n="3"/>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>NAPLES</head>
                        <p>THE SAVOY HOTEL. </p>
                        <p>First-Class Up-to-Date.</p>
                        <p>Suites and Rooms with Private baths and Balconies.</p>
                        <p>FOUR TENNIS COURTS</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>GND HOTEL DE LA VILLE,</head>
                        <p>FLORENCE.</p>
                        <p>OPEN ALL THE YEAR</p>
                        <p>STEAMHEATING.</p>
                        <p>Electric Light Throughout.</p>
                        <p>LIFT.</p>
                        <p>Winter Garden,</p>
                        <p>CONCERT, AMERICAN BAR.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>GRAND HOTEL ROYAL.…..GRANDE BRETAGNE.</head>
                        <p>LUNGARNO, ACCIAOLI.</p>
                        <p>FIRST CLASS OPEN ALL THE YEAR.</p>
                        <p>CHIOSTRI, Propr.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>THE MODERN HOTEL</head>
                        <p>LUNCARNO. FLORENCE.</p>
                        <p>APARTMENTS WITH PRIVATE BATHS.</p>
                        <p>Hot and cold running water in every room. Central Heating</p>
                        <p>AUTO-GARACE. MODERATE TERMS.</p>
                        <p>DELLA CASA &amp; SONS, <hi rend="italic">Propr</hi>.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>PEGLI.</head>
                        <p>HOTEL MEDITERRANEE.</p>
                        <p>FIRST CLASS.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cols n="3"/>
                    <cb n="2"/>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>LUCERNE</head>
                        <p>HOTEL SCHWEIZERHOF</p>
                        <p>First Class throughout</p>
                        <p>HAUSER BROTHERS, Proprietors.</p>
                        <p>(Switzerland)</p>
                    </div>
                    <cols n="6"/>
                    <cb n="3"/>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>ALASSIO.</head>
                        <p>ITALIAN RIVIERA.</p>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL MEDITERRANEE.</p>
                        <p>First Class. On the Sea Shore.</p>
                        <p>SEA BATHING.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cols n="3"/>
                    <cb n="2"/>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>THE FOUR BEST HOTELS IN GENEVA</head>
                        <p>Switzerland</p>
                        <p>Hotel NATIONAL – Hotel De Luxe with large park.</p>
                        <p> '' DES BERQUES Family House.</p>
                        <p> '' METROPOLE – First class house with moderate charges.</p>
                        <p> '' DU LAC – Central position Cook's OFFICE in the Hotel.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>SALSOMAGGIORE</head>
                        <p>1 ¼ hours from MILAN – ITALY – 6 hours from FLORENCE.</p>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL DE THERMES.</p>
                        <p>FIRST CLASS. EVERY MODERN COMFORT.</p>
                        <p>RITZ &amp; PFYFFER Propr</p>
                    </div>
                    <cols n="6"/>
                    <cb n="4"/>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>HOTELS EN ROUTE</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>VENICE </head>
                        <p>Grand Hotel</p>
                        <p>First Class.</p>
                        <p>EVERY MODERN COMFORT.</p>
                        <p>Large Terrace on the Grand Canal.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>ROYAL HOTEL DANIELI.</head>
                        <p>FIRST-CLASS HOTEL.</p>
                        <p>Situated in the Finest and Healthiest part of the Town</p>
                        <p>Railway Ticket Office in the Hotel.</p>
                        <p>All modern comforts.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>HOTEL BRITANNIA.</head>
                        <p>First class hotel in the best position with garden on the Grand
                            Canal.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>HOTEL MILAN-BRISTOL.</head>
                        <p>In the same position but more moderate.</p>
                        <p>CHARLES WALTHER Propr.</p>
                        <p>Same management HOTEL DE LA VILLE at Genoa.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>ROME.</head>
                        <p>HOTEL CONTINENTAL.</p>
                        <p>OPPOSITE THE STATION.</p>
                        <p>FIRST CLASS.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>NAPLES </head>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL DE LONDRES.</p>
                        <p>FIRST CLASS. CENTRAL.</p>
                        <p>Full South. Splendid view. Baths. Steam Heating. Perfect Drainage. Open
                            all the year round. Apartments with baths and toilet.</p>
                        <p>DELVITTO, POGGIANI, CAMPIONE, Propr.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>CONSTANCE (Germany.)</head>
                        <p>INSEL HOTEL ON THE LAKE.</p>
                        <p>Most interesting Hotel Ancient. Dominican Convent now converted into a
                                <hi rend="bold">First Class Hotel</hi>. 300 Beds. Tennis. Fishing.
                            Rowing.</p>
                        <p>M. BRUNNER, Manager.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>HOTEL CATTANI.</head>
                        <p>ENGELBERG.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>BRUNNEN.</head>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL BRUNNEN.</p>
                        <p>FIRST CLASS.</p>
                        <p>Magnificent Situation </p>
                        <p>ON THE LAKE.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>THUN (LAKE OF THUN.)</head>
                        <p>BERNESE OBERLAND.</p>
                        <p>PENSION ITTEN.</p>
                        <p>FIRST CLASS FAMILY HOUSE.</p>
                        <p>Surrounded by Woods. Magnificent view of the Jungfrau, Monch, and Eiger.
                            Swiss Chalet attached with private apartments and Baths. OWN FARM.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>THUN (LAKE OF THUN.)</head>
                        <p>HOTEL BEAU-RIVAGE.</p>
                        <p>Beautiful New Hotel.</p>
                        <p>First Class. Electric Light. Central Heating and Every Modern Comfort</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>ALGIERS.</head>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL ST. GEORGE. </p>
                        <p>Mustapha Superior. First-Class in every respect.</p>
                        <p>HOTEL DE LUXE.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NORTHERN ITALY (Continued) and The ITALIAN LAKES.</head>
                    <p>VENICE is a 5 hours journey by rail from Milan, and one of the most
                        delightful places imaginable to pass a quiet stay. The total absence of
                        vehicular traffic strikes one as very strange; no horse, cart, carriage or
                        bicycle is to be seen, and yet there is the sound of life at every turn. The
                        approach to Venice from the Adriatic is unlike that of any other sea port.
                        The town seems to be gradually, like Aphrodite, born of the sea. No hills
                        behind, no stretches of rock, but first the tops of Campaniles appear above
                        the horizon, then slowly the whole glittering town rises like a fairy mirage
                        out of the calm lagoon.</p>
                    <p>Going northwards from <hi rend="italic">Milan</hi> you make the tour of the
                        beautiful Italian lakes.</p>
                    <p>COMO, the birthplace of the younger Pliny, is reached in one-and-a-quarter
                        hours by train by way of Monza.</p>
                    <p>Boats leave Como frequently for the other towns on the lake, which is very
                        beautiful, and the scenery on either side going up the lake is most
                        enchanting. CERNOBBIO is a charming spot; then come <hi rend="italic"
                            >Tremezzo</hi>, <hi rend="italic">Cadenabbia</hi>, and <hi rend="italic"
                            >Menaggio</hi> with the prettily-situated town of <hi rend="italic"
                            >Bellaggio</hi> opposite. The walk from <hi rend="italic">Tremezzo</hi>
                        along the shore of the lake to <hi rend="italic">Menaggio</hi> is most
                        enjoyable. A steam tram runs from <hi rend="italic">Menaggio</hi> to <hi
                            rend="italic">Porlezza</hi> on Lake Lugano in three-quarters of an hour,
                        then steamer to Lugano in two-and-three-quarter hours.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SWITZERLAND.</head>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Switzerland</hi>, the heart of Europe, has been described
                        as "A cluster of delights and grandeurs."</p>
                    <p>LUGANO is some 20 miles from Como and reached by train in one-and-a-half
                        hours. It has a population of 10,000 people and is charmingly situated on
                        the Lake of Lugano, amidst lovely Italian scenery. Around it rise M. San
                        Salvatore, M. de Caprino.and M. Generoso.</p>
                    <p>LOCARNO may be reached by rail from Bellinzona in forty minutes. This pretty
                        town, situated at the top of Lake Maggiore, has a mild climate and is an
                        excellent winter resort. The church Madonna del Sasso, situated above the
                        town, is worth a visit, as it contains interesting paintings, “Entombment,"
                        by Ciseri, and ‘Tho Flight into Egypt,” by Bramantion.</p>
                    <p>LUCERNE—A striking picture on the Lake of Lucerne facing the Rigi and Pilatus
                        and the snow-clad Alps.</p>
                    <p>In and around the town the walks are charming, and the excursions to be made
                        from Lucerne by boat, rail, etc., are very numerous.</p>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">The Lake of Lucerne</hi> abounds in delightful excursions,
                        those to the <hi rend="italic">Rigi</hi>, <hi rend="italic">Pilatus</hi>,
                            <hi rend="italic">Burgenstock</hi> and <hi rend="italic">Sonnenberg</hi>
                        needing a special visit each. Other excursions on the lake can be made by
                        steamer, and the ever-changing scenery on the trip from <hi rend="italic"
                            >Lucerne</hi>, to <hi rend="italic">Fluelen</hi> is a source of delight
                        to the lover of nature.</p>
                    <p>BRUNNEN, charmingly situated on the most beautiful part of the Lake of
                        Lucerne, commands magnificent views of lake and mountain scenery. Along the
                        Lake of Uri from Brunnen to Fluelen runs the famous <hi rend="italic"
                            >Axentrasse</hi>.</p>
                    <p>THUN (on the Lake of Thun) half an hour from Berne and one hour from
                        Interlaken. Quiet and quaint; sheltered from winds; just the place to rest
                        and recuperate. Beautiful walks, through woods, and along the lake shore.
                        Kursaal, Concernts, Casino, Races, Tennis, Boating, etc.</p>
                    <p>THE BERNESE OBERHAND. – INTERLAKEN, a favourite summer resort and the best
                        centre for making excursions in the Oberland, abounding in fine walks and
                        views. There is a magnificent view of the <hi rend="italic">Jungfrau</hi>
                        from the Hoheweg, a fine avenue of walnut trees, the chief resort of
                        visitors. Interlaken is also not far from the famous waterfalls, <hi
                            rend="italic">Giessbach</hi>, <hi rend="italic">Trummelbath</hi> and <hi
                            rend="italic">Staubbach</hi>. Then also the glaciers of <hi
                            rend="italic">Grindelwald</hi> and view from <hi rend="italic"
                            >Murren</hi> and the <hi rend="italic">Schynige Platte</hi> are sights
                        not to be missed.</p>
                    <p>CHATEAU D’OEX. 3,500 ft above the sea on the new Electric Railway between
                        Montreux and Interlaken, surrounded by magnificent scenery, with pure dry
                        air. Much frequented by English people in Summer and Winter.</p>
                    <p>ZURICH on the Gothard route. Direct communication with Northern Europe.
                        Largest town in Switzerland, beautifully-situated on the lake of Zurich.
                        Theatres. Big Concern Halls. Boating on the lake. Excellent schools. The
                        National Museum.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GREECE and IONIAN ISLES.</head>
                    <p>Many people visit Greece after wintering in Egypt, as it is so easily reached
                        from Alexandria ; the climate in April is charming. The best steamers are
                        those of the Khedivial Mail Co. and the Russian Steam Navigation Co.</p>
                    <p>If possible tourists should arrange to be in Athens for the Orthodox Easter
                        in order to witness the Good Friday and Easter Eve ceremonies, and to be
                        present at the dancing on the Easter Tuesday festival held at Megara for
                        which a special train is run from Athens.</p>
                    <p>It is worth while to spend a few days in CORFU on account of the beauty of
                        the scenery. There is also good snipe and quail shooting to be had.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="6"/>
                <div type="section">
                    <head>HOTELS EN ROUTE,</head>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>VENICE</head>
                        <p>LIDO (Venice) VENICE </p>
                        <p>From Venice or Lido, charming trip on the lagoon, 12 min. by steamboat.
                            CLIMATIC STATION AND SEA BATHS, WITH CHINESITHERAPIC INSTITUTE. Express
                            between the station and Lido for the Hotels.</p>
                        <p>BAGNI LIDO (Venice) </p>
                        <p>The most important bathing station in Italy, Café-Restaurant and Terrace
                            on the sea. Hydrotherapic Institute, Concerts daily. Frequented by the
                            highest classes of society.</p>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL DES BAINS. </p>
                        <p>Adjoining the sea. First-class hotel with dependencies &amp; Chalets. 200
                            rooms &amp; saloons. Electric light. Aqueduct. Every modern comfort.
                            Delightful residence, without any mosquitos.</p>
                        <p>THE GRAND HOTEL, LIDO .</p>
                        <p>Hotel with its dependencies (Swiss Hotel) in the most delightful
                            situation of the Lido at the landing place, five minutes walk from the
                            bathing place. Wonderful view of the Lagune of Venice. Room from 3 lire,
                            with board from 8.50 per day. No mosquitos. Very dry and safe air. </p>
                        <p>Address-SOCIETE BAGNI. LIDO, VENICE ITALY</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head> ST. MORITZ (ENGADINE) SWITZERLAND.</head>
                        <p>The Grand Hotel St. Moritz,</p>
                        <p>A New First Class Hotel</p>
                        <p>WITH EVERY MODERN CONVENIENCE </p>
                        <p>Address all enquiries to THE MANAGER.</p>
                    </div>
                     <div type="advert">
                        <head>LAKE OF COMO (CERNOBBIO.)</head>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL </p>
                        <p>VILLA D'ESTE</p>
                        <p>First-Class House. Finest situation on the lake. Immense Park and
                            Gardens. Moderate charges. Omnibus at Como Station.</p>
                        <p>T. DOMARE, Manager.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head> LUGANO. </head>
                        <p>HOTEL BEAU-REGARD </p>
                        <p>and CONTINENTAL. </p>
                        <p>FIRST CLASS MODERN HOTEL. </p>
                        <p>Splendid Situation. </p>
                        <p>I. F. HELMSHAUER, Prop. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>LUGANO (Lake of Lugane) </head>
                        <head>GRAND HOTEL METROPOLE ET MONOPOLE.</head>
                        <p>STRICTLY FIRST CLASS.</p>
                        <p>A. BROCCA, Proprietor.</p>
                        <p>Also of the GRAND HOTEL, LUGANO.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>LOCARNO </head>
                        <head>THE GRAND HOTEL.</head>
                        <p>OPEN ALL THE YEAR.</p>
                        <p>Strictly first class. Every Modern comfort. Terminus of the St. Gothard
                            Railway. Magnificent Winter and Spring Resort. Best stopping place on
                            the Italian lakes. Beautiful Walks excursions. English Church. Tennis
                            and Golf. Central Heating. </p>
                        <p>This Hotel has lately been enlarged with 90 rooms, and apartments,
                            sitting rooms, and apartments with private baths.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>LUGANO. </head>
                        <p>HOTEL ST. Gotthard and Terminus.</p>
                        <p>Finest situation overlooking the Lake. Comfortable. Family House. </p>
                        <p>I. LANDRY.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>LUGANO.</head>
                        <p>HOTEL DES ANGLAIS.</p>
                        <p>THE ONLY HOTEL ON THE LAKE.</p>
                        <p>Quite New. English Management.</p>
                        <p>B.W. DOYLE, <hi rend="italic">Prop</hi>.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head> INNSBRUCK (Tyrol) </head>
                        <p>CARL KAISER'S PENSION-HOTEL. </p>
                        <p>Splendid situation, overlooking river and valley, surrounded by fruit,
                            conifer and rose gardens. Modern comforts and home-like, Library,
                            English and American papers, Baths Mariages, good table and Sanitary
                            arrangements.</p>
                        <p>Specially suitable for those requiring rest, quietness, and change of
                            air. Capital headquarters for excursions. Post, Telegraph, Telephone,
                            Dark Room,. Terms moderate for either short or long stay. English
                            spoken. Apply for prospectus.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head> INTERLAKEN. </head>
                        <p>THE SAVOY HOTEL. </p>
                        <p>QUITE NEW. </p>
                        <p>Splendid Situation. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>CHATEAU D'OEX </head>
                        <p>THE GRAND HOTEL.</p>
                        <p>The newesty and most up-to-date, thoroughly First Class and replete with
                            every modern comfort.</p>
                        <p>ELECRTIC LIGHT, CENTRAL HEATING, PRIVATE BATHS.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>HOTEL BERTHOD.</head>
                        <p>The Most Comfortable First Class Family Hotel.</p>
                        <p>EVERY MODERN COMFORT.</p>
                        <p>Berthod Brothers, <hi rend="italic">Proprietors</hi>.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>TANGIERS</head>
                        <p>HOTEL CECIL.</p>
                        <p>HOTEL DE FRANCE.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>TUNIS.</head>
                        <p>GRAND HOTEL DE PARIS</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>Hotel de Londres.</head>
                        <p>CONSTANTINOPLE.</p>
                    </div> 
                     </div>
                <cols n="4"/>
                <cb n="1"/>
                <div type="section">
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>SALSOMAGGIORE (Italy.)</head>
                        <p>A pleasantly situated village lying in the valley between Piacenza and Parma, rapidly becoming famous 
                            for its waters, which are very rich in bromine and iodine and the richest in the world in lithium, 
                            strontium, and ichthyol, and have been successfully used in the treatment of scrofula, rheumatism, 
                            tuberculous affections, ladies complaints, etc.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cb n="2"/>
                    <div type="advert">
                        <head>Grand Hotel Milan</head>
                        <p>FIRST CLASS. EVERY MODERN COMFORT.</p>
                        <p>R. FERRARIO, Proprietor.</p>
                    </div>
                    <cb n="3"/>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LAKE OF LUCERNE. </head>
                        <p>Palace &amp; Grand Hotel Axen-Fels.</p>
                        <p>World-wide reputation.</p>
                        <p>Best Spring resort. 2,200 ft. above the sea. Every comfort.</p>
                        <cb n="4"/>
                        <p>The leading Hotel for English and American families. Electric Railway
                            from Brunnen to Axen-Fels. The magnificent Park and Woods have nearly a
                            mile frontage on the Lake.</p>
                        <p>Best Spring Resort. 2200 feet above the Sea. Every Comfort.</p>
                        <p>Level Wooded Walks.</p>
                        <p>P, Schnack, Proprietor &amp; Manager</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
